why this brand chose real sets over AI
for their ad campaign. See, AI
production is not always a solution. And
here's an example of an ad campaign
where the brand insisted on building a
real set to show their product
underwater surrounded by the cichlid
fish to create this realistic deep blue
ocean look with the sunlight beaming
through all in real time. Now, you know,
typically for a commercial campaign, we
create one to two highly detailed
product photos a day. often shooting in
plates to showcase the product in its
best light. But this particular project
took a different approach. Here we aim
to capture everything in a single in
camera shot by building an underwater
set in real time. No composits staying
true to life. To enhance realism, the
bottle was shot underwater in a very
special customuilt optically wide glass
tank to avoid any grain tint. We also
chose vertical dimensions for the glass
tank to create photos in both 4x5 and
9x6 aspect ratios for the digital
campaign straight in camera. I opted for
continuous lighting over flash,
mimicking how our eyes perceive sunlight
in the real world. Now, we also chose
not to retouch certain imperfections on
the product to maintain its
authenticity. Here's the result. Let me
know your thoughts in the comments and
I'll see you all in the next one.
Cheers.